Kerwin Thompson

(321) 315-3842 · kerwindows@yahoo.com · Linkedin | GitHub | Portfolio |

REACT DEVELOPER

Innovative Application Developer with over 3 years of industry experience and extensive programming knowledge. Incorporating a unique blend of technical expertise and artistic creativity. Exceptional front-end skills, coupled with proficiency in the LAMP Stack and MERN Stack, creating visually stunning and functional websites and web applications that leave a lasting impression.

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Web Development, Object-Oriented, Programming, PHP, Laravel, ReactJS, Node, ExpressJS, REST API, Webpack, JavaScript, JQUERY, Redux, Redis, Linux, Git, GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, NGINX, Google Cloud, HTML, CSS, BOOTSTRAP, Figma, Canva, VSCode, WordPress, Drupal, Microsoft Office, Adobe Photoshop

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-stack Software Engineer

Cyversify Ltd 2020 – Current

- Contributed to expansion of company footprint, by spearheading the development of numerous web-based applications and synthesize and disseminate complex information for small and large businesses.
- Developed and contributed to both front-end and back-end code, including application structure, database selection and creation, UI/UX design and logic.
- Improved company code integrity through code refactoring and meeting industry standardization. **Tech Stack:** Javascript, React, NodeJS, PHP, SQL, RESTful API, Google Cloud

System Administrator

Caribbean Union College

2019 - Current

- Developed an SIS platform for a school to manage student attendance, records, and HR functions.
- Achieved a 30% improvement in attendance tracking accuracy and reduced administrative workload by 40% through a comprehensive record management system.
- Implemented an easy-to-use interface resulting in a 20% increase in user adoption and maintained the platform with 99% uptime and a 15% improvement in system performance.

IT Administrator

Caribbean Union College

2016 – 2019

- Spearheaded directive for new ICT infrastructure that increased productivity by 50%.
- Added financial recordkeeping functionality to database, minimizing workload for the accounts department by 70%.
- Pushed for and built online registration website, improving administrative productivity by estimated 80%, saved school 20% in paper expenses and minimized registration time by 60%.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Practicum US

Software Engineering Certification

2022 - 2023

University of Hertfordshire, Hatfield, Hertfordshire

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

2016 - 2018

First Class Honours

University of Trinidad and Tobago

2003 - 2005

Advanced Diploma in Electronics Engineering Technology